Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/zianggnguyen (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Mobile Design
Project Management
3D Animation

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

Giang Nguyen

Senior Product Designer

Vietnam

Summary

I'm currently a Product Designer based in Ho Chi Minh city, focused on enhancing Web/app's UX & UI and building Design Systems. I enjoy exploring everything and am adept at retaining new technology and application. My everyday goal is to create simple, intuitive, and beautiful experiences and build concrete foundations for sustainability and scalability.

Experience

Freelance
UX/UI Designer
October 2019 - Present (5 years 6 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Create wireframes, UI Design, prototype for Web, mobile app.

Collaborate with stakeholders (HR, PM, BA, UX/UI Designers, Content writers ...)

I have delivered various projects in the following fields:

- Blockchain (Web3 Real-estate Protocol)
- ERP system for Ed-tech
- ERP system for NGO
- Interior Design
- E-commerce

etc.

Medicia

Senior Product Designer November 2022 - October 2024 (2 years) Singapore

Revamp and design product of Oncology medical & healthcare solutions for patients, caregivers, doctors and admins (Mobile app & Desktop app) from diagnosis, treatments to palliative care, to provide a simplified and

sophisticated, more streamlined, accessible and personalized experiences to patients and doctors.

Craft and iterate on the end-to-end flow and prototypes on mobile and desktop.

Implemented Design system to successfully reduce design shipping phase from 6 months to 1 month and increase app loading speed to 300%.

Cryptocurrency - Blockchain Senior Product Designer April 2021 - January 2023 (1 year 10 months)

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including product managers, developers to define and deliver product requirements.
- Market & competitor research to come up with optimal solutions to improve product's UX and UI.
- Work closely with FE, BE developers, QAs to ensure the feasibility of the proposed UX/UI solution.
- Collaborated with UX writer to enhance product's copywritings & usability.
- Conducted user research and testing to gather insights into user needs and behaviors, and used these insights to inform design decisions and validate prototypes and designs.
- Created wireframes, high-fidelity prototypes, design system and visual designs for desktop, mobile, and web applications.
- Participated in design reviews and feedback sessions, and incorporated feedback into designs.
- Stayed current with the latest design trends and technologies, and recommended design-related tools and processes.
- Participated in hiring process (CV screening, interviewing...) to build design team.
- **Products:**
- Trading webs/mobile app
- **UX:**
- User testings, user interviews
- User flow, wireframe, high-fidelity prototypes.
- Copywritings

- Design system
- Responsive UI for website, mobile app
- Figma auto-layout components
- Illustrations, icons

Hoozing

2 years 6 months

UX/UI Designer

February 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 9 months)

Vietnam

- Work with CEO, CTO to clarify user needs about new features, define the scope to balance time & resources of the company.
- Research, come up with optimal solutions to improve product's UX and UI.
- Work with Developers, BA to ensure the feasibility of the proposed UX/UI solution
- Collaborate with Marketing Dept, Sales Depts and HR Depts to enhance product usability.

Products:

- Rental website/ mobile app for tenants
- Mobile app for agents
- Company's management system website

UX scope of work:

- · Organize usability testing sessions
- Create user flow, wireframe, high-fidelity prototypes.

UI scope of work:

- Build company's design system
- Design responsive UI for website, mobile app
- · Create illustrations, icons, videos

Property manager

May 2017 - January 2018 (9 months)

Vietnam

Work with landlords:

Answer landlord's queries regarding properties and photography.
 Solve landlord's related problems.

Work with team:

- Support photo team (take photo, retouch)
- Training for photo team & admin team

• Build and manage team's KPI outcome standards & SOP.

Education

University of Economics and Law Bachelor's Degree, Economics · (2011 - 2015)

Eggcademy